<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Science Camp:\n%c[255,245,240,218]What is it you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Science Camp:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Wait a moment, I am going to disable the security system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="first_bunker_fake_sms3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Science Camp:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Done, you may go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="volk_sasesc_bar4">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Now we can talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bun_swatoy_rush_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]%c[255,160,181,169]Messer:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey you, stop!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radar_na_tochke_govlab_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]You're on your own from here - we're not going in there with you, our orders are to hold this area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="kill_actor_svd_dolina">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Unknown sniper:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Where are you going, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hy_punk_dont_shoor_my_rat">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey, he's shooting at our rats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blacened_pp">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Oh, hey! Come on over, let's talk!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="start_bar_one_timer_0">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Major Kravtsov:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Come in, let's talk. You'll find me at our base. I'm waiting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="novic_leaded_dead_sms_slizen">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Slug:\n%c[255,245,240,218]What the hell? Is he fucking dead?! Get over here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="spawen_monolit_na_kordone_komandira_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey, you! Go to the building next to the water tower. I need to talk to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sms_esc_doki_band">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Incoming Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Bro, come out, alright? Relax, I just wanna talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_washe">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Attention, everyone! From now on, the stalker known as Messer has decided to become a murderer! There's now a bounty on his head - let him serve as another example of how not to treat your fellow stalkers! If you are listening, Messer, you may still get a chance to atone for your sins... If you manage to get to me before someone else teaches you a good lesson...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_killar_pre">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]What are you doing?! I'm going to tell everyone you are a fucking murderer if you kill one more stalker, you hear me?! You'll be dead before you even realize it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jaba_ohrene">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey, are you out of your mind?! These are my guys! They're guarding my bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="komandir_zdohnah">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Messer, what the fuck?! Is he dead?! Why the hell did I send you down there?! You still have amnesia, what am I gonna tell the troops?! Get over here, now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="infor_glob_rad_palba">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]PDA:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Attention! Critical radiation contamination! Check the suit for leaks or leave the contaminated area immediately!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="voy_dolineaa">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Messer, the soldiers have organized a raid on the bandits near your location, so be careful not to run into them. A couple of hours ago an army jeep left Cordon - there were 6 or 7 soldiers - and they were carrying some serious equipment with them. See if you can come back after they duke it out, you may be able to get some nice stuff from the aftermatch. Anyway, if you find anything interesting for me, I'll be in touch.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oobrataan">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Zyablikov:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Thanks for your help... I'd prefer to be left alone now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="njvis_oka_sch">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Stalker, come here, got something to discuss. I'm here, by the slope of the mountain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_heliequp_smsone">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Professor:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Great, look towards the road to the Bar. When you see the helicopter, head towards the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="barman_group_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]%c[255,160,181,169]Barkeep:\n%c[255,245,240,218]What's going on with the group? Damn it, Messer...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="messer_fonar_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Yes, it seems to be him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="messer_fonar_sms2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Dwarf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]I want to ask you about...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Stalker, you've probably heard of the Bar by now, right? The place where stalkers gather and such? I can tell you the Barkeep is interested in you, but he won't be happy if you go to them empty-handed. There's a house in the Dark Valley, and the Barkeep is very interested in some documents that are supposed to be inside... You should go take a look around.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]... This loot will be your pass to the elite, you'll practically rise to the top instantly. However, you can't get into the Dark Valley without some specialized gear - there's some kind of building in the area that generates maddening psi waves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lonewolf_gar_smsm3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]You need some psi-blockers. The troopers went on a raid there recently, and it looks like they're all dead. I have information that a couple of soldiers made it out to the Garbage. I'm sure one of them has some. They were last seen at a crossing where a small creek runs off of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Stalker, watch out, there's a pseudo-dog!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Wait, don't go! Messer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Well, here we are. The room is all yours so make yourself comfortable, rest properly. The doors are only locked from the inside, and once the door is open, the room will be considered to be unnocupied. You can't lock it from the outside, and anyone will be free to come in and bring or take whatever they want... And, you have to be ready to evacuate at a moment's notice. Don't worry about it, though, just don't open the door until you're ready to go, and then we'll go to the Bar. We'll catch up with a drink or two.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_bar3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]You awake? Alright, let's go then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_volk_sasesc_stop">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Lone Wolf:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey, Messer! Wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zagon_bandosa">
		<text>Incoming message:\nSprout: Hey, bro, come with us! We got that bandit bastard that smoked seven of our guys pinned down, help us whack the son of a bitch!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bad_timer_del_novic_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Zob:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey man, you got my gun...? What, you're keeping it for yourself? Alright, fine. Hope it doesn't get you far, asshole.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dofhodi_kvestpat">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Messer, come in... So here's the situation: I need you to get an artifact for me. It's called the "Toad's Eye". Funny, I know - It's located in the northern area of the Garbage. I sent a squad there before, but I lost contact with them... I'm told the area specifically has no anomalous activity, but people are afraid to go there regardless. Shouldn't be a problem for you, though... I think. Sending the coordinates your way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_jaba_zavod_doki_escsa">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]One more thing. That Flesh you shot stole some documents a courier of mine had on him while taking a nap in the factory, if you can believe it. He said the Flesh had some kind of lair on the roof, the docs may be up there. Find them and bring them to me, alright? Seriously, don't bother coming back without them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_horok_ne_have_go_nazad">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]I don't get it, is he dead or something? What the hell were you looking at? I sent you to him, Messer. Come back to the bunker...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sms_esc_olr_kvest_3_zametki_bio">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Oh, I forgot. There's a tab in your PDA to check the contacts of nearby stalkers that are within a radius of about 250 meters from you. You can chat with them if you want, just select whoever you want in the Contacts section. Some stalkers have some info about themselves in their profiles as well. Try to reach Digger via PDA when you are near him to test it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda_zarad_info_zaba">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Remember your PDA has a battery. Keep an eye on the charge level to avoid being left in the dark during an ugly situation...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_blowout_first_zaba">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]How are you doing, still alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_blowout_first_zaba_blok">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Messer, there's something going on at the checkpoint. I can't get any signal from there, it's like there's no one around. Weird. Listen, why don't you go check it out, quietly? Come back to me when you're done, and don't linger too long around the place...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Watchdog:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey stalker, we'll talk after we deal with these fucking dogs, alright?...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Watchdog:\n%c[255,245,240,218]How you feeling, rookie?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Crow's Eye:\n%c[255,245,240,218]He looks fine. And he's no rookie either, didn't you see the way he took down that pseudo-dog? Good shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pes_go_talk5">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Watchdog:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Yes... he's no newbie. Come, we need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bad_timer_gardolpsevdo">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Duty:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Watch out! There's a pseudo-dog! Focus that thing, kill it now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Duty Leader:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Fighters, take your positions! The dead are coming. Messer, this is your chance to make your mark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Duty Leader:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Chin up, men! Another wave is coming!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_zom3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Duty Leader:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Attention all! We are detecting strange interference in the air... Be careful...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bar_dolg_lider_stuka">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Duty Leader:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Okay, we've got the rat, all right... he's pushing our ammo to the left. Go to our merchant for the reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zagon_bandosa2">
		<text>Incoming message.\nAh... damn rats...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_one">
		<text>Incoming message.\nDamn it. I knew there was something wrong here. Let's just leave, guys...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_tri">
		<text>Incoming message.\nSergei: The group is dead... God damned bloodsuckers! What the hell am I supposed to do now...? Thanks for coming with me, stalker. I owe you one. If you need me, look for me at the Bar, alright? I need a drink after this mess...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_noobik_progulka_two">
		<text>Incoming message.\nFucking door.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_0">
		<text>I've got some special orders here...  Bring anything weird you find. You never know what kind of surprise the Zone will spring on you next time... Oh, and hurry. You're the only one on the look-out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_1">
		<text>Hey, are you outside the Cordon now? I was told a strange artifact was seen in that area. Bring anything strange you find. You never know what kind of surprise the Zone will give you next time. There's a tenfold fee for this unknown artifact, so hurry up, you're not the only one looking for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_zhaba_random_zakaz_2">
		<text>There's information about a special artifact nearby. Bring anything weird you find. You never know what surprise the Zone will give you next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hmm, looks like the source of the contagion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hmm, looks like the source of the contagion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_deadcity_paras_talk_to_dleader_sms">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Messer, this is the leader of the Duty faction. I'm waiting for you at my office. We need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Major:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hello, Rat, trying to do your business behind my back?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav4">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Rat:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hello, Major. I was acting solely on your instructions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Rat:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leave us two alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_krisa_gavgav2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Rat:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Do I have to repeat myself?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Incoming message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Max.\nIt's working! Let's run to the hall and see what's going on!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Incoming message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Max.\nThe light is on, my friend, the light is on!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Incoming message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Max.\nThis is it! This is what I was talking about!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_maxsms_cool4">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Incoming message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Max.\nYes, I'm coming to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rush_rostok_tmer_mochii">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Shit, there's someone out there, everybody be on the lookout!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_rush_rostok_tmer_mochii2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Group\nEveryone group up! Remember, our goal now is to get to the tunnel leading to Rostok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nOkay, it seems all is quiet, now. Come stalker, we'll discuss what to do next...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nKeep quiet... Everyone check your guns...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nThere's something there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead4">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nHalt! Let's take the bastards down! Whoa... who are these guys?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead5">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nOkay, put the guns away, guys. This is just an ID check. You try to run, you're gonna get shot. I'm dead serious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead6">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nWhat the hell?! Nail, go check it out. We're holding these ones, don't piss--</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead7">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nThere's nothing here! Let's go get these guys and get the fuck outta here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead8">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nYou! Get your backpack off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead9">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Black Slug\nFuck! Get the fuck away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead10">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nMesser! Get out of here, let's go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead11">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nMesser! Follow me, let's get out of here, hurry up! What the hell is this place!? That thing dragged you down here before I could get here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_progulka_prisli_plos_lead12">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Leader\nIt's quiet. Shit. Go to the bar, talk to the Barkeep about what happened. I'm not going with you, I have some things I need to take care of... Go!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass_hrom">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Chrome:\n%c[255,245,240,218]I think I got a signal. Wait a bit, our guys will give them a warm welcome. If you can, do us a favor and help our guys. I don't think they'll know who attacked them in the dark.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass_hrom2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Freedomer:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Quiet, boys. Let's try to go in, quietly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mg_sms_hey_punkass">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Monolith\nStalker, get out of here... this is none of your business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sms_val_garbage_bandits">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Hey, stalker! Come here, I have something for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]This password expired on 20.02.2012. Please enter a new password.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms2">
		<text>Fuck... Fucking Slug...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_olr_lab_2_door_unlocked_fake_sms3">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Uh, hey you, bro, come over here, just around the corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shakal_esc_sms1">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Jackal\nMesser, turn on your PDA and find me through the Contacts tab. I'll tell you what's going on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_shakal_esc_sms2">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Message:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Connection lost.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
