<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="ps_hum_dtart">
		<text>It's been years. I don't remember much. The grid. Trucks. Men with knives. Lights. Pain. I remember the pain. I remember it well. Then there was fear and hunger. Dark. Cramped. There were many of us. There was no food, we were hungry. We ate each other. I remember the door opening. It was dangerous and very bright outside... We'd go out at night, when we couldn't see. Then we'd hide. From people like you. The hunger was gone, but the fear remained. The realization that we'd never get out of here. Not everyone could take it. I guess I'm the last of my generation. The new ones have it easier than we do. They don't know about life on the outside. They don't need it. They have the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_21">
		<text>Question time's over, now join us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_no_0">
		<text>No, I refuse to join you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_11">
		<text>So you're back. You destroyed the bio-installation at Lake Yantar, disabled the psi antenna on Radar, and even disabled the secret psi-field generator that was broadcasting the illusory Monolith into the heads of those who made it to the sarcophagus... Project C-consciousness is pleased, you have successfully completed your mission and are now eligible to join us, to become an instrument of the project.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_who_are_you_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_who_are_you_1">
		<text>I am a representative of Project C-consciousness. My function is to maintain the life and safety of the other members of the project. I'm here to integrate the new member into our collective brain network.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_0">
		<text>Project C-consciousness?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_1">
		<text>In 2005, the Common Consciousness experiment began, and the neural linking of five prisoners yielded positive results. The Common Consciousness or "C-consciousness" had slightly less power than five times the human intelligence. The C-consciousness awakened, showing frantic neuronal activity and nearly five times the information processing speed of the human brain. The criminals' previously erased memory was being filled in again... The precautions were insufficient - the researchers were not prepared for such events. Upon contact with one of the sedated bodies, the C-consciousness group came under the control of two technicians and an attendant nurse. Further, the entire research block where the experiment was being conducted came under control with incredible speed. Instantly reacting, the leaders of the experiment completely isolated the entire block from the outside world. A deadly gas was pumped through the ventilation shafts. 28 human controlled bodies convulsed while C-consciousness tried unsuccessfully to find an escape route. It was calculating escape options by scanning the memory of the controlled bodies. The bodies began to die, but the C-consciousness had already discovered one-way windows through which the group of scientists observed the consequences of the experiment. With the help of strong telepathic influence, the group was brought under control and the C-consciousness could hold nothing back. The personnel of the underground complex was taken under control and the power of the C-consciousness increased manifold. About 500 people were connected to C-consciousness... Now there are only six of the strongest left...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_0">
		<text>Was the 1986 catastrophe your work, too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_1">
		<text>No, we had nothing to do with it. Our experiment began after the Chernobyl accident.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_death_truck_0">
		<text>What are the death trucks?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_death_truck_1">
		<text>They're the transportation we use to take our agents to different parts of the Zone. Agents infiltrate the stalkers and perform the tasks they were programmed for without even realizing it. Unfortunately, more than half of the agents die during transportation, as the Zone is very unstable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_stalker_0">
		<text>What does the S.T.A.L.K.E.R. tattoo stand for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_stalker_1">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. is the name of a program to code a person to perform certain tasks. On the approaches to the center of the Zone, we've located several psi installations. The largest of them is known to you as the brain scorcher. Anyone who tries to get to the center of the Zone comes under our control. Then they are coded, become our agents and get a S.T.A.L.K.E.R. tattoo. By sending them around the Zone, we influence the course of events and ensure our safety.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_about_me_0">
		<text>What happened to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_about_me_1">
		<text>You're a loose cog in the machine. On one of your trips to the center of the Zone, you got too close to us. Our defenses against infiltration were supposed to be perfect, but you managed to find a way in that we didn't know existed. We could not allow our secret to be known by anyone else: mankind is not yet ready to learn the truth about the causes of the Zone. Therefore, we immediately began to code our agents for your destruction. For some unknown reason, the equipment malfunctioned, and we did not notice that you yourself were among the stalkers who fell under our control. As a result, you were tasked with killing yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_next_0">
		<text>What happens next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_what_next_1">
		<text>What happens next is up to you. The zone is slowly but steadily growing. Our power is barely enough to contain the flow of noospheric energy. You can join us, our powers will increase and we may be able to control it. You could destroy us. Then the noosphere energy will flow unimpeded into the Zone, and there is no telling where it will lead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_0">
		<text>Why did this happen here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_1">
		<text>The Chernobyl nuclear power plant was the most suitable place for our experiments. Firstly, after the 1986 accident there were very few people left here, so we could work without fear. Secondly, the plant provided us with the energy we needed to run the plants. Thirdly, there were powerful antennas near the power plant, which were used in experiments to influence people's consciousness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="oso_yes_0">
		<text>I agree to join you.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
