<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_0">
		<text>What the hell do you guys do here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_1">
		<text>Uh, we're just busting some suckers. If you hadn't told me Barkeep sent you, you'd be busted, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_2">
		<text>Don't you know how to make money any other way?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_3">
		<text>Listen, stalker, do you even care?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_4">
		<text>Don't get mad, I'm just asking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_5">
		<text>You've been sent here in peace, and you're asking questions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sz_leader_di_6">
		<text>Well, I'd better go. I'm not as welcome here as I was the first time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil2_0">
		<text>I brought your friends.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil2_1">
		<text>Good! So listen, there's a door at the entrance to the lab, code 4578. We're gonna have a little fun. I talked to the Barkeep, and it's true you have an assignment from him. Well, I'm happy to help. Just watch out, the lab's a creepy place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil2_2">
		<text>Bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil_0">
		<text>Hey, Slughorn's given the go-ahead. Let's go to their base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil_1">
		<text>Come on, we know the way, just follow us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dibil_2">
		<text>Right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_kvest">
		<text>Sure, it's a start, buddy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_0">
		<text>Hey, did you send me that text? What was that about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_1">
		<text>Okay, first of all! Who the hell are you to be messing around? This is our place, and stalkers have no roads here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_2">
		<text>Relax, I'm on a mission from the Barkeep. I'm looking for some kind of lab. You've never heard of it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_3">
		<text>From the Barkeep? Hmm. Alright. What? A lab? What are you doing in there, buddy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_4">
		<text>I told you, I'm on a mission. So you know where the entrance is?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_5">
		<text>Yeah, I do, and I'll tell you! It's up there in the north, where the compound is. But the thing is, the entrance to the lab is sealed and you can't get in that easily... But you can get in. If you work for us. I'm the only one who knows the access code, so you don't have a choice. So, listen, some assholes from Cordon decided to play tough guy. They came here in a group of three to scare the local monsters. Well, and eventually got stuck, they've been here for the second day on the rock, some way to fight back, it seems. They've already sent us an SOS signal 20 times! Anyway, go there and bring these assholes to our camp, we'll give them an educational talk with the boys. They're out here on the east side of the cliff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_6">
		<text>Alright.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_7">
		<text>Go on, get going, and then we'll see what to do with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_71">
		<text>What do you need them for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_72">
		<text>That's a hell of a thing to say. I told you on the way in, this is our territory, and stalkers have no way in. We're gonna punish our stalker brothers. We've already got crosses for them. We're humane, ha!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_73">
		<text>You'll kill them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_74">
		<text>Well, yeah. What do you want? I'll make you a bargain, I'm not greedy now. Hmm?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_75">
		<text>No, I'll get them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="slizen_dialog_755">
		<text>I'll bring them in. Okay, I know how to kill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_4111">
		<text>Yeah, I.D. You'll find your death there, that's for sure. I haven't seen anyone around here in months, and here you are. Password, okay. They change from time to time, so it's not like it's gonna work for you. Well, let's say for a good gun, I'll tell you. AS "Val", for example, and vodka for us, five bottles. If you bring it, we'll talk. Here... And if you can't find a "Val" with vodka, bring five jars of jelly instead. Only full ones! That's it. go. Oh, one more thing. When you're in Bar, give Dead Man's regards to the Snitch. See you later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="val_escort_nap1_dialog_41111">
		<text>Oh, that's right. So, listen, about two weeks ago, some nerd in an orange outfit was sniffing around, trying to get in. He's been hanging around for, like, two days. He was looking for someone to go down there with him. He was pissing himself. So we couldn't take it, he dropped the profits, so we kicked his ass. That's the code I saw on his PDA. 4230. Write it down or you'll forget it, heh.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
