<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_hand_torch_super">
		<text>A flashlight that has a modified bulb and voltage regulator, giving it better brightness. Quite useful at nighttime or in areas with little or no lighting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
		<text>Smoke Grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-_anom7h14">
		<text>Anomalous 7N14 round</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-anom">
		<text>An anomalous 7.62x54mmR round that's had a piece of the Gravi artifact embedded in it, improving its ballistic performance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular-name">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza_short">
		<text>"Groza"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_akms_podstvol">
		<text>A underbarrel grenade launcher for the AKS-74 prototype.\nAmmunition:\nVOG-25\nVOG-25R</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_akms">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_akms_short">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_akms_desc">
		<text>Modification of the AKM assault rifle with a folding metal rifle butt, a design similar to the AKS. Due to the poor quality of the 7.62x39 intermediate cartridges in the Zone, the weapon wears out quite quickly, and the poor accuracy, compared to more modern assault rifles, makes it not the best tool for far shooting. \nAKMS used mainly among conscripts and stalkers who cannot afford a better weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_ak74">
		<text>AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_ak74_desc">
		<text>Kalashnikov machine carbine for 5.45mm shell. Kalashnikov machine were developed for existed martial doctrine – most economy, reliable and simple, handiness and shooting accuracy suffered from that. Weapon of military stalkers and middle-class stalkers in the Zone. Clip capacity 30 shells. Basic ammunition - 5.45x39 FMJ, Armor-piercing bullet 5.45x39 AP.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-igla">
		<text>Igla MANPADS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-igla_desc">
		<text>The Igla is a third-generation MANPADS. It works both in the conditions of natural (background) heat and artificial interference (spoofing countermeasures). To this day, it remains one of the best systems in its class.\n\n Usage:\nActivate the ground power supply.\n5 seconds will proceed until the missile is prepared for combat, which consists of cooling down the homing head to working temperature and rotating the tracking system gyroscope.\nAim the launcher at the target. When the target appears in the field of view of the homing head, a stream of thermal radiation enters the coordinator. If the flow is greater than the minimum sensitivity of the coordinator, a sound signal plays. The target is locked on, and the launch tube is opened.\nWhen the sound signal plays, the missile is launched. The power supply maintains operation for about 40 seconds after being turned on. If no missile is launched during this time period, the missile is rendered unusable. Locking onto a target at an angle less than 20 degrees between the target and the sun is impossible.\n \nAmmunition:\nIgla missile</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla">
		<text>Igla missile</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla_s">
		<text>Igla missile</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-igla_desc">
		<text>A heat-seeking missile that's used by the Igla MANPADS. The missile uses a two-channel infrared GOS system, which allows for the heak-seeking system to differentiate between natural and artificial thermal noise. When the rocket impacts something, or is in close proximity to a target, the detonation fuse will go off. To improve fuel efficiency, the rocket itself uses a two-stage ignition system so it can maintain flight for extended periods of time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss_m">
		<text>A gauss rifle that comes with a enlarged detachable magazine, having a larger capacity of rounds.\n\n Ammunition:\nGauss rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife_m1">
		<text>The personal knife from a stalker named 'Scrap'. The handle is badly worn, but if you hold it, you'll notice that it fits perfectly in your hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon_addon_scope_m">
		<text>PSO-1 Optical sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon_addon_scope_susat_m">
		<text>SUSAT Optical sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36_m">
		<text>This specific G36 has been altered by spraying powder from a grounded up gravitational artifact onto the barrel, improving overall accuracy.\n\nAmmunition:\n5.56x45mm SS109,\n5.56x45mm AP,\nM209 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_m1_new">
		<text>This Vintorez has a dedication to honor the memory of a deceased stalker written on the side. In addition to the inscription, various adjustments were made to the weapon, which result in superior accuracy, but poorer reliability.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x39mm PAB-9,\n9x39mm SP-6,\n9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Ammo">
		<text>Ammunition</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shock rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70mm Buckshot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12x70mm Buckshot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>12x76mm Dart rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
		<text>12x76mm Dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76mm Slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76mm Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.45x39mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.45x39 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5.45x39mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm SS109</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 SS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39">
		<text>.30 Russian Short</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39_s">
		<text>7.62x39mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
		<text>7.62x54 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54R 7H14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7.62x54R 7H14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54mm BP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x54 BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9x18mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9x18 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>9x18mm +P+ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9x18 +P+</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>9x18mm PBP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp_s">
		<text>9x18 PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9x19 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19mm JHP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39mm PAB-9 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9x39 PAB-9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
		<text>9x39 SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>Gauss rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_s">
		<text>Gauss rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209">
		<text>M209 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_s">
		<text>M209</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b">
		<text>PG-7VL warhead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>PG-7VL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25">
		<text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25r">
		<text>VOG-25R grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25r_s">
		<text>VOG-25R</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>The .45 ACP caliber full metal jacket round, used by the Colt M1911, Sig-Sauer P220, USP Compact, and the Desert Eagle has enjoyed popularity for more than a hundred years thanks to its heavy bullet and a relatively small propelling charge. As a result, the bullet in this round is relatively slow but highly accurate and provides considerable stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>This unusual .45 ACP caliber round, used by the Colt M1911, Sig-Sauer P220, USP Compact, and the Desert Eagle, is comprised of a jacketed soft point bullet with an expanding hollow and a steel core. It is a combination of jacketed expanding soft point and armor piercing bullets, benefiting, from the advantages of both and, suffering from their downsides.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>Standard 12-gauge round filled with 6mm shot. Highly lethal at close range. Only suitable for use with smoothbore weapons - specifically the TOZ-34, the TOZ-66, the Maverick 88, and the SPAS-12.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-dart">
		<text>A specialized shotgun round that's similiar to a slug, but more pointed. Its fins add stability, resulting in increased accuracy. The massive steel body of the bullet can penetrate any body armor. This round is used by 12-gauge shotguns - the TOZ-34, the TOZ-66, the Maverick 88, and the SPAS-12.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>This heavy 12 caliber slug round is normally used for hunting big game, but is also good for other purposes. Instead of piercing, this hefty slug simply crushes through armor. This round is used by 12-gauge shotguns - the TOZ-34, the TOZ-66, the Maverick 88, and the SPAS-12.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>This cartridge is a 5.45x39 caliber armor-piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries, and in the Zone it's used by the AK-74, the RPK-74, the AKS-74U, and the AKS-74 prototype. The bullet contains a hard-alloy armor piercing penetrator. Effective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>This cartridge is a 5.45x39 caliber improved piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries, and in the Zone it's used by the AK-74, the RPK-74, the AKS-74U, and the AKS-74 prototype. It provides better accuracy than the 7.62x39mm caliber rounds thanks to its reduced recoil and a 100 meter increase in range.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>A common NATO military 5.56x45 caliber armor piercing round, known under its SS190/M855 index, widely used by Western security agencies and special services. In the Zone, this round is used by the for the L85A1, the LR-300, the SG-550, the G36, the FN-2000, and the M134. Effective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>A standard issue NATO 5.56x45mm caliber round specially designed for accurate automatic fire, known under its SS109 index. Provides good ballistic characteristics, having been designed on the basis of a hunting round. In the Zone, this round is used by the for the L85A1, the LR-300, the SG-550, the G36, the FN-2000, and the M134.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x39">
		<text>Intermediate all-metal cartridge 7.62x39mm, 1943 model. Due to the long period of storage in local abandoned army arsenals or dubious contraband, it is of poor quality, which affects the short-term wear of weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>This cartridge is a 7.62x54mmR caliber sniper round with a steel penetrator that was specially designed for the SVD sniper rifle, and it can also be used by the SVU sniper rifle, the PKM light machine gun, and 7.62x39mm AK rifles that have been rechambered to accept this cartridge. Unlike the machine gun round, the 7N1 provides tight groupings and excellent penetration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>This cartridge is a more specialized 7.62x.54mmR caliber high precision armor-piercing sniper round. In the Zone, this round is used by the SVD and the SVU sniper rifles, the PKM light machine gun, and 7.62x39mm AK rifles that have been rechambered to accept this cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>This 7.62x54mmR caliber round has an armor-piercing bullet, making it effective at taking out armored targets from a distance. In the Zone, this round is used by the SVD and the SVU sniper rifles, the PKM light machine gun, and 7.62x39mm AK rifles that have been rechambered to accept this cartridge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>A full metal jacket round with a steel penetrator and a lead core under a metal jacket. In the Zone, this round is used by the Makarov PM, the PB, the Fort-12, and the Stechkin APS. Provides good stopping power but is ineffective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>This round contains a bullet with enhanced stopping power, while its European +P+ designation indicates "overpressure ammunition" with a 30% increase in muzzle velocity. While somewhat more effective against body armor, it's still fairly underwhelming against armored targets. In the Zone, this round is used by the Makarov PM, the PB, the Fort-12, and the Stechkin APS.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>A round with a jacketed soft point bullet that deforms slightly on impact instead of expanding, giving it a limited armor piercing effect. In the Zone, this round is used by the Makarov PM, the PB, the Fort-12, and the Stechkin APS.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>This basic 9x19mm caliber round with a jacketed bullet has good characteristics while being simple to produce. The round is popular due to the fact that international conventions prohibit the use of expanding ammunition in combat. Ineffective against body armor. In the Zone, this round is used by the Browning HP, the Walther P99, the Beretta 92FS, and the GSh-18.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>This 9x19mm caliber round has a jacketed hollow point bullet with an expanding, hollow interior. This provides high stopping power and low ricochet propensity. Used by police and for self-defense. Ineffective against body armor due to its low penetration potential. In the Zone, this round is used by the Browning HP, the Walther P99, the Beretta 92FS, and the GSh-18.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>The SP-6 is a subsonic assault rifle round with a jacketed soft point bullet with a hard steel core that protrudes from the casing. Requires a silencer for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. Effective against body armor. In the Zone, this round is used by the VSS Vintorez, the AS Val, the OTs-14 Groza (and its prototype), and the VSK-94.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>The PAB-9 is a subsonic sniper round with a bimetallic casing. The round contains a steel core with a gap behind it that is filled with lead. Requires a silencer for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. In the Zone, this round is used by the VSS Vintorez, the AS Val, the OTs-14 Groza (and its prototype), and the VSK-94.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-sp5">
		<text>A sniper round for the VSS Vintorez, the AS Val, the OTs-14 Groza (and its prototype), and the VSK-94. It has a subsonic bullet which, due to its heavy weight and specialized design - it can penetrate most bulletproof vests at a range of up to 400 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
		<text>These gauss rifle magazines consist of both rounds and a battery using a capsulated fragment of an energy artifact as a power source. They are manufactured using high-tech equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m209">
		<text>The M209 is a 40 mm grenade for the M203 underbarrel grenade launcher. It has a 5 meter kill zone, and it's also used by the integrated underbarrel grenade launcher that's used by the FN-2000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-og-7b">
		<text>The PG-7VL is a high explosive, tandem charge warhead grenade that's for the RPG-7V. It's devastating against mutants, stalkers, troops, and lightly armored vehicles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25">
		<text>The VOG-25 is a fragmentation grenade for the GP-25 Kostyor underbarrel grenade launcher. This grenade has an effective radius of five meters. The VOG-25 grenade is also used by the OTs-14 Groza's underbarrel grenade launcher (along with its prototype), and RG-6 revolving grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25r">
		<text>The VOG-25R is a improved fragmentation grenade for the GP-25 Kostyor underbarrel grenade launcher. This grenade has effective radius of five meters - but fefore detonation, the grenade jumps up to a height of about a meter, which increases its lethality. The VOG-25R grenade is also used by the OTs-14 Groza's underbarrel grenade launcher (along with its prototype), and RG-6 revolving grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-f1">
		<text>A defensive hand grenade, with fragments capable of piercing medium-level body armor. The grenade has an effective range of 7 meters. Stalkers get F1 grenades from trading with the military bureaucrats, who write them off as having been used for fighting mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-gd05">
		<text>A smoke grenade. These are used to put up smoke screens, which serves as an effective means of visual cover. Once the grenade is thrown it takes around 10 seconds for the smoke screen to expand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgd5">
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small effective range of 5 meters. These are often used by stalkers to "smoke out" mutants due to its relatively low cost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>A single shot, front loaded, rifled underbarrel grenade launcher for assault rifles made in Warsaw Pact countries. The firing mechanism is self-cocking, with a manual safety catch and automatic shot prevention if incorrectly installed onto a rifle.\n\nAmmunition:\nVOG-25 grenade\nVOG-25R grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>A modified M203 grenade launcher that has been shortened by three inches, attached to weapons by means of a Picatinny rail. Thanks to a changed mount, this grenade launcher is widely used around the world.\n\nAmmunition:\nM209 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope">
		<text>The PSO-1 is a very common Soviet-made optical scope. It attaches to weapons by means of a Dovetail mount, which is standard for weapons used by former Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope-susat">
		<text>A 4x fixed zoom scope produced primarily in Western countries. It attaches to weapons by means of the NATO-standardized Picatinny rail. Often used for accurate fire from small arms at medium to long range.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>An effective silencer which can be modified on the go as required. The body of the silencer around the barrel contains a roll of fine brass mesh, while the front comprises a set of metal diaphragms with holes for the bullet to pass through. The set includes adaptors and sealants for most weapons. Normally used to thin out enemy ranks without drawing attention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>This Kalashnikov has a modified bolt and gas system, increasing its rate of fire.\n\nAmmunition:\n5.45x39mm FMJ,\n5.45x39mm BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16">
		<text>The TOZ-66 is a side-by-side shotgun, originally designed for hunting animals, but it's also lethally effective at putting down hostile stalkers or soldiers. It has good accuracy for close to medium ranges. The TOZ-66 is often seen in the hands of rookies, and merchants always hold them in stock for sale.\n\nAmmunition:\n12x70 Buckshot,\n12x76mm Slug,\n12x76mm Dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt1911">
		<text>An improved version of the classic Colt 1911 automatic pistol, which passed all the major armed conflicts of the 20th century with flying colors and entered the new millennium with confidence. Produced by dozens if not hundreds of arms manufacturers around the world in both standard and modified configurations. The weapon's only drawback, its mediocre magazine capacity, is largely compensated by the hard-hitting ammo it uses.\n\nAmmunition:\n.45 ACP,\n.45 ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000">
		<text>This futuristic-looking weapon with a bullpup layout is actually a mass produced modular system, comprising a rifle grenade complex with a computerized fire control system and a 40-mm grenade launcher. Despite its bulky appearance, the weapon is highly ergonomic, easy to use and benefits from good reliability.\n\nAmmunition:\n5.56x45mm SS109,\n5.56x45mm AP,\nM209 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort">
		<text>A Ukranian-made pistol predominantly used by law enforcement organizations. Compared to the Makarov PM, the Fort-12 has better higher accuracy, better ergonomics and has a larger magazine. These pistols make it into the Zone in large numbers thanks to the sale of defective weapons, which suffer from technical flaws in early design models. Despite this, the pistol is in demand among stalkers thanks to its good combat characteristics.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x18mm FMJ,\n9x18mm +P+,\n9x18mm PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36">
		<text>The G36 is a new addition to the Western-made assault rifle family, which differs significantly from previous models in the series built on an automatic foundation with a semi-open bolt assembly, this weapon is more like American automatic gas-operated assault rifles with a short-stroke gas piston system. These changes ensure that the rifle is a first-rate example of a modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic.\n\nAmmunition:\n5.56x45mm SS109,\n5.56x45mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss">
		<text>This gauss rifle is a highly accurate, technologically advanced weapon. It was developed in secret laboratories located inside the Zone. The weapon operates by accelerating bullets to extremely high speeds using a system of electromagnets, which provides incredible stopping power with virtually no recoil. The weapon is powered by using capsulated artifact fragments stored in the batteries.\n\nAmmunition:\nGauss rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza">
		<text>This assault rifle combined with a grenade launcher, which is similar to the AK series, was specifically developed for rapid response units. The main differences are its 9x39mm caliber ammunition, bullpup layout and extensive configuration options. This weapon is highly valued by military stalkers due to its ability to kill enemies wearing body armor behind improvised cover at a distance during urban combat, as well as its excellent stopping power.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x39mm SP-5\n9x39mm SP-6\n9x39mm PAB-9\nVOG-25\nVOG-25R</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hpsa">
		<text>A modified version of the Browning Hi-Power pistol from the first half of the 20th century, which is as reliable, powerful and accurate as the original. Pistols of this series deserve their reputation as one of the best handguns of the 20th century and are in great demand in the Zone.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x19mm FMJ,\n9x19mm JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife">
		<text>A hunting knife. If you need to take someone out quietly, this knife is the perfect weapon for the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-lr300">
		<text>The LR-300 is the latest weapon from the Z-M Weapons company owned by Allan Zitta. Allan is well known for his extensive experience in developing new pistols based on Colt M1911. The LR-300 is a new stage in the AR-15's development. LR-300 stands for 'Light Rifle, 300 meters' - indicating that its maximum effective range is 300 meters. The upper and lower receiver support a new type of interconnecting operation-rod gas system, which allows for a short barrel and folding stock, giving the weapon its compact profile. One of the features of its new gas system is its diverted recoil, which helps to keep the weapon on target with no muzzle climb. \n\nAmmunition:\n5.56x45mm SS109,\n5.56x45mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5">
		<text>This submachine gun has gained popularity around the world thanks to its reliability, ease of use and accuracy. Over the last few decades the MP5 was in service with special armed forces and police units worldwide. Not surprisingly, having flooded the global black markets, it eventually made its way to the Zone.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x19mm FMJ,\n9x19mm JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5">
		<text>HK 53</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
		<text>The HK 53 is a carbine variant of the HK 33KA3 with a shortened barrel that's 221 millimeters long, a extended flash supressor and forend that's similar to HK MP5. No underbarrel grenade launcher or bayonet knife can be installed. This weapon has been manufactured since 1975 and is mainly used by special forces.\n\nAmmunition:\n5.56x45mm SS109,\n5.56x45mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pb">
		<text>This pistol, a variant of the Makarov PM, was developed in the second half of the 20th century for special forces and recon units. The front of the pistol's barrel is has an integrated silencer attached to it, while the bolt mechanism is short, which prevents a back-moving spring from being located inside it, and it is therefore situated in the weapon's handle. Although obsolete, the weapon is still effective in the right hands.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x18mm FMJ,\n9x18mm +P+,\n9x18mm PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pm">
		<text>Designed and manufactured by Izhevsk Machine Engineering Plant in Russia for police and military armament since 1951, this Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defense handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including its short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x18mm FMJ,\n9x18mm +P+,\n9x18mm PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg-6">
		<text>This revolver-type grenade launcher uses six rifled front-loading barrels, identical to underbarrel launcher attachments. The drum is also front-loading. The RG-6 is widely used for rapid suppression of enemy positions and, when in the open, attacking defended fixed targets or fighting particularly tough monsters.\n\nAmmunition:\nVOG-25 grenade\nVOG-25R grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpg7">
		<text>This grenade launcher from the 1960s made its way into the Zone from army depots. The RPG-7V is a smoothbore, single-shot, recoilless rocket launcher system with an open-rear tube. It comes with a PGO-7 x2.8 optical scope. Although its huge size and weight make it an unlikely choice for stalkers, given its huge destructive power and ease of use, it has found admirers in the Zone.\n\nAmmunition:\nPG-7VL warhead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig220">
		<text>The SIG-Sauer P220 is the only remaining mass produced model of the globally renowned P220 series. This weapon has earned a reputation for its excellent ergonomics and accuracy, and while its magazine is relatively small, it benefits from powerful ammo and a mechanism that functions like a Swiss watch. Some believe the P220 to be the best mass produced .45 ACP caliber handgun there is and it has certainly got a following among experienced stalkers and mercenaries.\n\nAmmunition:\n.45 ACP,\n.45 ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd">
		<text>An army sniper rifle that has been on the market for more than fifty years and has earned its reputation for exceptional reliability and ease of use. The SVD is normally used by armies in countries that are part of the ex-USSR to improve the effective range of its units, but stalkers respect this weapon for its armor-piercing properties, which allows it to penetrate mutant hide and anti-ballistic body armor.\n\nAmmunition:\n7.62x54mmR 7N1,\n7.62x54mmR 7N14,\n7.62x54mmR BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu">
		<text>A modernized version of the SVD sniper rifle that's a compact, bullpup version of it - made to the specifications of Russian special forces units. It allows faster precision fire and is considerably lighter, while its single shot firing accuracy at short and medium range is similar to that of its predecessor. These qualities have earned it the admiration of countless stalkers.\n\nAmmunition:\n7.62x54mmR 7N1,\n7.62x54mmR 7N14,\n7.62x54mmR BP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34">
		<text>The TOZ-34 is a extremely common over-and-under hunting shotgun, offering better protection against mutants than a pistol, thanks to its accuracy and stopping power. It's used mostly by rookies on the outskirts of the Zone. It has been in production since 1964 at the Tula Arms Plant.\n\nAmmunition:\n12x70 Buckshot,\n12x76mm Slug,\n12x76mm Dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-usp">
		<text>Impeccable reliability and durability combined with excellent accuracy are the main noteworthy features of the USP Compact. Its minor drawbacks include its considerable size, relatively high center of gravity and massive bolt, which make it difficult to conceal but do not outweigh the weapon's positive features. The weapon is especially popular with the Zone's veterans.\n\nAmmunition:\n.45 ACP,\n.45 ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val">
		<text>A modified version of the silent Vintorez sniper rifle, this assault rifle was designed as a weapon meant for special forces. The rifle's primary purpose is effective fire against enemies employing modern personal protection equipment without revealing the shooter's location. Thanks to its integrated silencer and 9x39mm caliber round with a heavy subsonic bullet, the weapon's noise and muzzle flash have been reduced to a minimum.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x39mm PAB-9,\n9x39mm SP-6,\n9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez">
		<text>The VSS Vintorez is a specialized military sniper rifle purpose-built for silent, flashless sniping during special operations where avoiding early detection of the shooter may be critical. It provides high armor-piercing capability and stopping power, as well as being equipped with an integrated sniper and optical scope. Highly rated by many stalkers despite its small magazine.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x39mm PAB-9,\n9x39mm SP-6,\n9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-walther">
		<text>The Walther P99 is a excellent Western pistol known for its reliability, high capacity magazine and good accuracy, as well as being among the most ergonomic handguns in its class. One of the most widely used pistols in the Zone, both among professionals and rookies who can afford it.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x19mm FMJ,\n9x19mm JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>The Mossberg Maverick 88 is a Western smoothbore shotgun that is extremely popular around the world due to its great reliability and quick reloading speed. It's particularly valued for its functionality by the Zone's hunters. All of its parts are coated with an anticorrosion compound.\n\nAmmunition:\n 12x70Buckshot,\n12x76mm Slug,\n12x76mm Dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_coll">
		<text>A hybrid version of the VSS Vintorez and the AS Val, combining the best features of both weapons. This weapon has a 20-round magazine and very accurate automatic fire. The rifle's 2x scope is tailored for short to medium-range combat. Additionally, the trigger mechanism has been modified to reduce wear and tear during firing.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x39mm PAB-9,\n9x39mm SP-6,\n9x39mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-f1">
		<text>F-1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-gd05">
		<text>GD-05 smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade-rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Weapons1">
		<text>Weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hpsa">
		<text>Browning Hi-Power</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_hpsa_short">
		<text>FN HPSA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_usp">
		<text>USP Compact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_usp_short">
		<text>USP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>GP-25 Kostyor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-scope">
		<text>PSO-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-scope-susat">
		<text>SUSAT sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>Rapid-firing AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-bm16">
		<text>BM-16</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-colt_m1">
		<text>Colt M1911</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-colt1911_short">
		<text>M1911</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-eagle_m1">
		<text>Eagle-M1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fn2000">
		<text>FN-F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fn2000_short">
		<text>F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fort">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-fort_m">
		<text>Fort-12M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-g36_short">
		<text>G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-gauss">
		<text>Gauss rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-gauss_short">
		<text>Gauss</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza">
		<text>OTs-14 "Groza"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-groza_m1">
		<text>OTs-14-4A Groza</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-lr300">
		<text>ZM LR-300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-lr300_short">
		<text>LR300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-lr300_m1">
		<text>ZM LR-300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-mp5">
		<text>MP5A3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-pb">
		<text>PB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-pm">
		<text>Makarov PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-pm_short">
		<text>PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rg-6">
		<text>RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rg6_m1">
		<text>M209 RG-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-sig220">
		<text>P220</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svd_m1">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svu">
		<text>OTs-03 SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-svu_short">
		<text>SVU</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-val">
		<text>AS "Val"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-val_short">
		<text>"Val"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-val_m1">
		<text>AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez">
		<text>VSS "Vintorez"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez_short">
		<text>VSS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-walther">
		<text>Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-walther_short">
		<text>P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-walther_m1">
		<text>9x18 Walther P99</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>Mossberg Maverick 88</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez_coll">
		<text>Improved VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_bm16_full">
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn_bm16_full">
		<text>The TOZ-66 is a side-by-side shotgun, originally designed for hunting animals, but it's also lethally effective at putting down hostile stalkers or soldiers. It has good accuracy for close to medium ranges. The TOZ-66 is often seen in the hands of rookies, and merchants always hold them in stock for sale.\n\nAmmunition:\n12x70 Buckshot,\n12x76mm Slug,\n12x76mm Dart</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-aps">
		<text>Stechkin APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-aps">
		<text>The Stechkin APS is an machine pistol developed during the late 1940s and early 1950s, and was officially adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1951 alongside the Makarov PM. The APS is intended for arming officers taking direct part in combat operations, as well as for soldiers and sergeants of special units.\n\nAmmunition:\n9x18mm FMJ,\n9x18mm +P+,\n9x18mm PBP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_knife_old_rotten">
		<text>An old army knife. The blade itself is worn and pitted, but still sharp.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
