<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_medi">
		<text>Medical Supplies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_custom_treasure_rukzak">
		<text>Backpack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_custom_treasure_rukzak_desc">
		<text>This specific backpack - a military surplus one that's rugged and waterproof, normally comes with the most common and popular stalker suit. You can take it off and use it to make a secret stash in a secluded place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_firematches">
		<text>Matches</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_af_merger">
		<text>Transmutator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sleeping_pills">
		<text>Sleeping pills</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_pda">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_snotvornoe">
		<text>An over-the-counter sleep aid. If taken, it'll induce drowsiness quickly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_water">
		<text>Water bottle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_sigaret">
		<text>A regular Dream brand cigarette. Smoking is bad for you, but it'll help take the edge off and calm you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="battery_change_name">
		<text>Battery for devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_capsule">
		<text>Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="battery_change_short_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_battery_change">
		<text>A removeable battery for PDAs (and other compatiable devices) that can be recharged. You can use it to increase your PDAs power charge, and to find out what the current charge of your PDA is. The most common flashlight used in the Zone does not accept this type of battery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_sigaret">
		<text>Cigarette</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_detector_siniy">
		<text>A detector for measuring anomalous activity. To make measurements you need to take the device in your hands and activate it near the source of anomalous energy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="detector_siniy_name">
		<text>Detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_water">
		<text>A plastic bottle filled with cool and refreshing drinking water, great for quenching thirst. These are normally imported into the Zone by traders who buy them in bulk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_rat_food_coocked">
		<text>A rat that's been cooked with fire. Its much more nutritious than a uncooked rat, and the heat from the fire has sterilized it, making it safe to eat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_crow_food_coocked">
		<text>A crow that's been cooked with fire. Its much more nutritious than a uncooked crow, and the heat from the fire has sterilized it, making it safe to eat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_psy_stabilizator">
		<text>This drug relieves the effects of various kinds of psionic radiation. It surpasses other benzodiazepine and abenzodiazepine tranquilizers in terms of how strong it is; it has a very strong anxiolytic (anti-anxiety) and tranquilizing effect; it also has a pronounced anticonvulsant, myorelaxant (muscle relaxant) and sedative effect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="psy_stabilizator_name">
		<text>NEURO-A psionic stabilizer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_anti_beshenstvo_dog_caps">
		<text>A pill blister pack with a single dose of Chloroquine in it. Chloroquine gives protection against rabies. Most dogs in the Zone are infected with rabies, and will spread it if they attack anyone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="anti_beshenstvo_dog_caps_name">
		<text>Chloroquine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_exo_acum_ob">
		<text>This servo power cell is meant for exoskeletons. In order to supply an exoskeleton with power, you must attach this power cell to your belt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_description_outfit_stalker_golmar">
		<text>This suit was made by the stalker who gives by the name 'Golmar'. It has various particles from artifacts embedded in its fabric, giving it useful anomalous properties. Pieces from an gravity artifact have been sewn into this suit's flaps, allowing its user to hover slightly above the ground, increasing height its user can jump, and potentially softening the impact from long falls. This suit also increases its user's carrying capacity by an additional 20 kilograms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_outfit_name_outfit_stalker_golmar">
		<text>Golmar's suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad">
		<text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_antirad_sh">
		<text>Anti-radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-heavy">
		<text>Heavy stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-light">
		<text>Light stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Arm-medium">
		<text>Medium stalker gear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bandage">
		<text>Bandage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_binocular">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_bread">
		<text>Bread</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_killers_documents_desc">
		<text>A polyethylene file that contains numerous documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva">
		<text>Tourist's Delight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_conserva_short">
		<text>Tourist's Delight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Detect1">
		<text>Anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Devic">
		<text>Instruments and devices</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-PDA">
		<text>PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="device-torch">
		<text>Flashlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="battery_change_headlamp_short_name">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 18kg. Details: Protects the body from Jelly, Burnt Fuzz, most anomalies and physical damage. The torso and back are protected by built-in bio-metallic plates. The suit is equipped with an airtight, reinforced plastic helmet and two oxygen bottles. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 8 kg. Details: Protects the body from weak anomalies and physical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
		<text>Protective suit. Weight: 12 kg. Details: Protects the user from Jelly, Burnt Fuzz, many anomalies and physical damage. Equipped with an airtight helmet and an oxygen bottle. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
		<text>An "EXP-4" scientific protective suit with an airtight red helmet. Weighs 11 kg. It protects the body from fire, acid gases, a variety of anomalies (including "Burnt Fuzz"), and mechanical damage. Equipped with two oxygen cylinders. Warning: with continuous use it will become damaged and torn.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
		<text>Army binoculars with adjustable (up to 7.5 diopters) magnification.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect3">
		<text>A device that detects the presence of anomalous formations, along with hot pockets of radiation. The distance to the anomaly is indicated by the how frequently the light emits. To ensure reliability, readings should be done when stationary.\nMaxinum number of anomalies that can be detected and registered simultaneously - 4.\nDetection radius - 10 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
		<text>An outdated, first-generation anomaly detector. It emits a light when it detects anomalies. The distance to the anomaly is indicated by the how frequently the light emits. To ensure reliability, readings should be done when stationary.\n- does not detect all anomalies\n- can give false or inaccurate readings\n- If you have this device, you can scan items in your backpack for radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect2">
		<text>A device that detects the presence of anomalous formations. The distance to the anomaly is indicated by the how frequently the light emits. To ensure reliability, readings should be done when stationary.\nMaxinum number of anomalies that can be detected and registered simultaneously - 3.\nDetection radius - 10 meters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
		<text>A PDA is an indispensable device in the Zone for any stalker, useful for things such as cataloging data or maintaining a journal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
		<text>A flashlight that has a fairly powerful bulb. Quite useful at nighttime or in areas with little or no lighting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
		<text>An opioid-based medication used to treat pain, used by many stalkers in the Zone as a quick fix.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
		<text>No bakers have ever been identified in the Zone - so it's safe to assume that this bread comes from the Big Land, but it's neither contaminated nor radioactive, being fresh and quite edible. At least no complaints have been reported thus far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
		<text>Presumably, these canned rations were looted by stalkers from an army ration depot. Without any kind of label on the can, it's hard to say for sure. Should still be good to eat, if you believe the best before date.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
		<text>For better or worse, this sausage - a mix of chicken and a soy substitute - is often a stalker's breakfast, lunch and dinner in one. Can be stored for a long time due to high preservative content.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
		<text>Vodka made by GSC. Goes down easy and considerably lowers the effects of radiation. Should be enjoyed in moderation.\nLoss of coordination.\nSlightly relieves the effects of radiation sickness.\nQuenches thirst.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
		<text>Perfectly filters out radionuclides from the body and reduces the impact of absorbed radiation. There's also a supplied bar of hematogen in a separate packet.\nPossible loss of coordination.\Provides treatment for radiation sickness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
		<text>A normal elastic bandage used to stop bleeding and prevent infection of wounds. For regular bleeding, carefully apply the bandage to the wound. For arterial bleeding, urgently tie the bandage around the affected area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
		<text>A general purpose single-use medical kit. Handy for treating various injuries - wounds, bruises, regular and chemical burns and various types of poisoning. In demand among stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_name">
		<text>Vicodin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
		<text>Vicodin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_equipment">
		<text>Equipment and food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Food">
		<text>Food</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_kolbasa">
		<text>Sausage</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit">
		<text>Health-13 Medkit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_medkit_short">
		<text>Health-13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Sci2">
		<text>EXP-4 suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vodka">
		<text>Vodka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector">
		<text>DA-2 anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector2">
		<text>UDA-14a universal anomaly detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector3">
		<text>DLF-5 detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_detector_descr">
		<text>This detector is designed to detect anomalous formations, as well as hot spots of radioactive contamination.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_guitar">
		<text>Guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_item_guitar">
		<text>A regular six-string guitar. Stalkers enjoy playing a tune while sitting around a campfire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_harmonica">
		<text>Harmonica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_item_harmonica">
		<text>A regular harmonica, the simplest musical instrument in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dimanit">
		<text>Dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_equipment_all_item_explosion">
		<text>Explosive</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hand_radio">
		<text>Radio</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
