<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="af_dummy_dummy_q1_desc">
		<text>It's a strange kind of artifact called a Dummy. It's stuck to the wall of my backpack. Gives off a faint greenish glow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>Jelly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_banka_s_holodcom">
		<text>Concentrate of the Jelly anomaly. When the jar is broken, a new anomaly is formed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_esc_vishka">
		<text>Unknown anomalous formation. Floats slightly in the air, while being quite heavy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-compas">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-compas">
		<text>An artifact with a bizarre shape resembling a spiral.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_art_kub">
		<text>Description: It has interesting and unpredictable properties. For example, it increases resistance to blowouts. Rumor has it that if you fall asleep with this artifact while under zombification, the disease can recede and the artifact itself will disappear....</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_art_kub">
		<text>Invisible Cube</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_lenss">
		<text>Description: A valuable and rare artifact. Object of sale, it has no studied properties, except one - it increases the body's resistance to high temperatures.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lenss">
		<text>Lens</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_spiral">
		<text>Description: an anomalous object of unknown origin that looks like a spiral. When worn on the belt, it causes a feeling of drowsiness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_spiral">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_steklo">
		<text>Description: transparent object, valuable from an aesthetic point of view.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_steklo">
		<text>Glass-like object</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_sterj">
		<text>Description: The only artifact of this type. A straight metal rod 43 cm long. On one of the sides it can be seen the clearly marked numbers "2465".
    Properties: Capable of quenching any type of energy without changing shape or showing any primary signs (heating or cooling). Non-radioactive, no dangerous effects have been detected.
    Application: Object of scientific research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_sterj">
		<text>Rod 2465</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>Description: Artifact with negative properties on the carrier's psi influence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_chernaya_busina">
		<text>Black bead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_lichinka">
		<text>Description: A shrunken larva of an unknown insect inside an oval glass object. It has the strange property of saturating its host.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_lichinka">
		<text>Larva</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>An artifact of the third degree of anomalous luminosity. Properties unknown, except one - increases resistance to radiation. It is known that artifacts of the anomalous luminosity class can react abnormally with other artifacts of the same class.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art_3_step_anom_svetim">
		<text>Artifact of the third degree of anomalous luminosity class</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_art460">
		<text>Artifact #460. An object with a negative degree of anomalous luminosity. Properties unknown. It is known for certain that artifacts of the anomalous luminosity class can react anomalously with other artifacts of that class.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-art460">
		<text>Artifact #460</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_black_kristal">
		<text>Artifact of unknown origin. Poorly studied specimen. It has the ability to increase its owner's muscle tone, allowing him to move for longer periods of time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-black_kristal">
		<text>Black Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_kolco">
		<text>Artifact of unknown origin. Has the ability to increase the wearer's muscle tone, allowing them to move for longer periods of time. Tends to degenerate with prolonged use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_kolco">
		<text>Ring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_studen">
		<text>Viscous substance. Ultra-hazardous colonies of mutated bacteria.\nSpecificity: Very dangerous anomalous formation, store only in a protected container such as an R1 capsule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_studen">
		<text>Stud</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>The result of artifact modification. Has forced properties of parent artifacts, including negative ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-af_gold_fish_black">
		<text>Black Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_studen_m1_desc">
		<text>The result of gene modification of the Jelly artifact. Protects against parasite spores, eliminates the possibility of contracting a disease.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_unknown_art_name">
		<text>Unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_st_unknown_art_desc">
		<text>An artifact with unknown properties.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Mercury Ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slime">
		<text>Radioactive bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Radioactive fragment</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-blood">
		<text>Toad's Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall">
		<text>Double pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Glass bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-drops">
		<text>Itch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-battery">
		<text>Disintegrator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>Pacifier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Dead Head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>Plasma</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-dummy-spring">
		<text>Washcloth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-flash">
		<text>Stinging absorbent cotton</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>Electric ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>Knot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fireball">
		<text>Transparent ball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>Strong needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gold-fish">
		<text>Strong gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-gravi">
		<text>Gravitational Artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-medusa">
		<text>Bagel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-mincer-meat">
		<text>Rusty Hair</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-night-star">
		<text>Magnet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Black thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>Needles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>Spikes</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-soul">
		<text>Black blobs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af-vyvert">
		<text>Weak gravitational artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
		<text>Consists of liquid metal of anomalous origin. It is formed after an emission, stays in contact with the body for a short time and then evaporates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
		<text>Cheap artifacts in the form of metal fragments and construction debris. It has no useful properties. Interesting to researchers only for radiation measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
		<text>Cheap artifacts in the form of metal fragments and construction debris. No useful properties. Interesting to researchers only for radiation measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
		<text>Unique artifact. The result of interaction between the Black Spike and the Meat Grinder. Rarely appears in anomalous clusters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
		<text>Appears in anomalous clusters. Protects against fainting, restores strength, shields against psi effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
		<text>Born in a springboard anomaly. This artifact can be found in few parts of the zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
		<text>It is formed by the "Heat" anomaly at high temperatures. Externally, it looks like a blackened drop-shaped formation with a glossy surface covered with cracks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
		<text>A super-artifact of an electro-magnetic nature. Directional disintegration field. When activated, it emits a powerful force field that instantly transforms any objects into "jelly". The origin of this thing is shrouded in a veil of scientific mystery. It is clear that it includes dielectric elements, but under what physical conditions it is formed - science does not know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
		<text>An artifact from a weak energy anomaly that has no practical use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
		<text>Super-artifact of the second level. Appears in anomalous clusters. Has the ability to scare away monsters while attracting a controller. When panicking monsters, it loses its anomalous energy and can vaporize. Level of anomalous energy: very high. Cost: very high.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
		<text>Artifact originated through a transmutation. High cost. A viscous substance resembling a sticky mass, but very strong. Tends to spread into crevices. Rumor has it that when this artifact is worn on the belt, it spreads into damaged areas of the suit and then solidifies there, thus patching holes and damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
		<text>Super artifact with an unstable gravitational field. A throwing object that, after hitting the floor or an obstacle, fires into a living body. Once hit, is fired at the next living body, until it falls or hits an inanimate object. After which it can be picked up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
		<text>Large flying fluff, leaves heavy burns when it hits a body. It accumulates in lowlands, pits and hollows. Rises into the air in a wind or explosion. Spewed from a buildup of "burning fluff."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
		<text>An outgrown case of Elektra anomaly activity. Apparently, you can get such a nice rounded shape by subjecting the anomaly to thermal effects. An expensive artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
		<text>The origin of this type of artifact, as well as the name is shrouded in mystery. Valued among the researchers of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
		<text>Artifact of thermal origin. A transparent shimmering sphere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
		<text>When you hold this mystery of the Zone in your hands, you can feel your skin becoming rough and less sensitive. It is still easy to penetrate with a bullet, but it is much harder to cut it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
		<text>It is generated by the "Funnel" anomaly. Elemental artifact with a directed magnetic-gravity anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
		<text>Elemental artifact with a directed magnetic-gravity anomaly. Has a variety with more pronounced anomalous properties - "strong gravitational artifact".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
		<text>Elementary artifact of gravitational nature. Has the shape of a torus, which explains its name. At least two varieties of this artifact are known - ordinary and "glass bagel".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
		<text>An elemental artifact of organic nature. A bundle of tough lichen fibers of a dirty rusty color. It has no useful properties. Item for sale.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
		<text>Various metal junk, which has been lying in gravitational anomalies for a long time, has acquired the ability to create a directed magnetic field of high intensity. This item is a fragment of a gear shaft of a gearbox. The magnet is a strong gravitational artifact with a strong unilateral gravitational anomalous effect, used to create gravity weapons and anti-gravity devices. Possesses surreal effects. Appears near the parent anomaly. It is not dangerous, so it can be picked up and does not necessarily need to be stored in a container. The artifact moves in every possible way: it dances and jumps up to half a meter, unsteadily hovers above the ground and shakes; it can hang on a wall or ceiling, which confirms its gravitational origin. From 15-20 meters the sound detector reacts to the artifact with a special sound. Has 1 level of anomalous energy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
		<text>Crystallizes in the anomaly "Stinging fluff". It removes radiation from the body naturally. That is, through the ears along with a certain amount of blood. Possible blood loss through other orifices as well. Occurs infrequently and is quite effective, which has earned it a stable price on the artifact market.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
		<text>Reminiscent of 10-centimeter needles. Appears in their parent anomaly, stuck in the ground and slightly rippling. Will not fall if set on a point; will also stay on a point if poked into a wall or ceiling at any angle. No danger, so they can be picked up and do not necessarily need to be stored in a container. From 3-7 meters, the detector reacts to the artifact with a special sound. Temporarily shielded from psi effects, blind dogs "lose track" of the carrier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
		<text>The result of the interaction between the "Stinging Fluff" anomaly and the body of an inattentive stalker. The spiky artifact prickles the body of the owner, no matter the way it's attached. But it also helps cleanse the body of radionuclides. Quite common and cheap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
		<text>Very rarely found near the "Carousel" anomalies. This artifact is very hard to find, and few people have even seen it. It has a pleasant shape and no less a pleasant price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
		<text>It is located near anomalies like "Funnel". When in contact with the body, it spreads directed radiation that increases stamina. Such an artifact is not difficult to find, and therefore the money given for it is small.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
