<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_120">
		<text>Don't interrupt. I'm about to give you something that's especially valuable in the zone-- information. If what they're saying about you is true. You probably don't know, there was a case. It was about half a year ago, kids from the neighboring villages all went to the Zone one morning. The authorities hushed it up. There was this guy who tried to do it. they called him Journalist. I met him once. He said the kids had gone deep into the Zone. And he either hired a pro, a "stalker by god" named Gunslinger, or he got that name over time... Anyway, somehow he's connected to this Gunslinger. -...and this Gunslinger he also went deep into the zone. But first, the Journalist was looking for something at the Agroprom Research Institute.  Documents. or his stash. And they say you're looking for Gunslinger too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_propusk_0">
		<text>How are you, stalker? What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_propusk_1">
		<text>Bloodsucker, my ass. I didn't see it while I was flesh-hunting. He snuck up from behind. Oh, shit. There's a stalker's stash hidden in the factory. Stalker. You ever heard that name? They said he was in the center, so I thought I'd check it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_propusk_2">
		<text>I see. Take it easy. Save your strength.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_propusk_3">
		<text>Ah, damn, monsters. Where did they come from? I barely made it out of there. But I got hurt pretty bad. You probably don't know, there was a case. It was six months ago, kids from the neighboring villages all went to the Zone one morning. The authorities hushed it up. There was a guy who tried to do it. Everyone here called him "The Journalist". I met him once. He said the kids had gone deep into the Zone. And he either hired a pro, a "stalker by god" named Gunslinger, or he got that name over time... Anyway, somehow he is connected with this Gunslinger, and this Gunslinger, he also went deep into the Zone. But first, the Journalist was looking for something at the Agroprom Research Institute... Documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joonnar_0">
		<text>Hi, one of yours sent me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joonnar_1">
		<text>Listen, we're in a bit of a pickle here. We've received information about a very valuable device with specific properties. It's here on Agroprom. It was supposed to be delivered to the scientists, but something must have gone wrong. You know. I have no interest in that device getting to Yantar. I don't think the Professor can do anything with it, the only thing he's good at is blowing stalkers away with impossible tasks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joonnar_2">
		<text>So what do you want me to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="joonnar_3">
		<text>Bring it to me. It's behind the main complex near the camp. We can't go in on our own because there's a possibility of surveillance. Do it, and the reward will be handsome, don't you worry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_talk_sos_agro">
		<text>%c[255,160,181,169]Toad:\n%c[255,245,240,218]Military stalkers are looking for something in the Agroprom territory. Be careful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stalker_talk_sos_agro">
		<text>Mayday! Somebody help me! I'm in the factory grounds, hurry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agro_olr_zavod">
		<text>The factory grounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hmm_agro">
		<text>Hmm.. Strange place..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
		<text>Tell me about this place</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
		<text>It's the territory of the Agroprom Research Institute. The building itself is in the southwest. The factory to the north is the institute's production and technical base. The buildings have been abandoned for a long time, and there's nothing to take there. But recently the military started to actively search for something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
		<text>There are legends about this institute. Before the accident in 1986 there was only a lonely building of the Institute of selection and genetics of cereals. And on the place of the plant there were experimental fields. After the accident the institute was closed and the fields were burned. Then they remembered, whitewashed the building, put a fence around it, and built barracks. The factory was built on the site of the fields. I don't know what the institute was doing there, but they obviously didn't spare any money.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
