<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="memuars">
		<text>Personal note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_beginning">
		<text>Who am I?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_beginning_text">
		<text>Damn it, it's all a haze now... I remember a car... They drove me somewhere for a long time and my whole body hurt... There was darkness... What happened before that? I've no idea... So confused... Now this fat guy calls me the Marked One, probably because of the strange tattoo on my arm, and then there's this weird mission to kill some guy called Gunslinger on my PDA... Is it even my PDA? Looking at Gunslinger's photo I'm not even sure if I knew him or not... Dammit! It's all like a bad dream you can't wake up from! What to do? Where to go? And worst of all: who am I? OK, OK, calm down, control yourself. The first thing I'll have to do is do some jobs for this Sidorovich. He claims to have saved my life after all... That shouldn't be too bad. I'll take a walk, calm down myself and perhaps my head will be clearer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid">
		<text>The first deep raid</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_deep_raid_text">
		<text>So, I am going on my first deep raid into the Zone. The target is the Agroprom Research Institute. I need to recover some documents belonging to a military expedition. Apart from the mission the trader gave me some information about an area to the North, on the way to the Zone's center, where the "brains boil"... Probably more of a legend than a fact, but since there's clearly something wrong with my head I probably should take a look at it and talk to some people. You never know - maybe I've been there before... Also, the trader told me that Gunslinger discovered a way to get through the area and the traders want to know it. Their reasons are clear - they want to access untouched artifact fields. Well, I'm going to help them, I guess.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_opinions">
		<text>First impressions</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_first_opinions_text">
		<text>Well, well... Got some fresh air, saw the local wildlife... Interestingly I seem to remember some of it already, but it's all in a haze... Had a chance to try the local "amusement" called anomalies... Judging by the fact that I survived I've probably come across them before, but my brain stubbornly refuses to remember... Sidorovich is one clever bastard - he knows he can use me almost for free and that's exactly what he wants to do. Still, maybe he'll help me find this bloody Gunslinger fella... He's my only connection with my past.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_fox_meet">
		<text>About Gunslinger</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_fox_meet_text">
		<text>Stalkers know about Gunslinger and that he was at the center, but no one has seen him in the Zone in months.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_provodnik">
		<text>Psi Brain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_provodnik_text">
		<text>I disabled the Psi Brain installation on Yantar. A message came through that the Professor now wants to talk... Well, I'll have to go there. I wonder if the path to the Swamps will be available? I'll have to check with him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_seryi_meet">
		<text>Meeting</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_seryi_meet_text">
		<text>Hopes of quickly finding out about Gunslinger are dashed - the information from the stash does nothing more than refer me to a stalker nicknamed Digger, who seems to know the location of Gunslinger group's stash... However, if the information is confirmed, then the stash is already something tangible, look, there I will find really useful information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_usefull_info">
		<text>Useful information</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_usefull_info_text">
		<text>The merchant didn't let me down and I'm grateful to him - gave me a thread in terms of finding Gunslinger. Specifically, a tip on a stalker named Fox. He's in the neighborhood, asking for help. The merchant thinks he knows Gunslinger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend">
		<text>The Legend of the Wish Granter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend_text">
		<text>Learned a local legend. They say there's a certain Wish Granter in the depths of the Zone. The location is unknown, somewhere in the center of the Zone. Like, you go to him, and, uh. and life gets easier. Mm-hmm. Maybe go to him and tell him I want to remember everything! - and the end of my problems. But I'm sorry to waste my will, in case I remember everything and it turns out that I'm a rare bastard... it would be a shame. I wonder how many wishes he grants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_seriy_flash_info">
		<text>I've managed to locate Gunslinger PDA. Miscellaneous notes. There's a reference to a certain Journalist. Also a mention of some sort of pieces of information scattered throughout the Zone. Various reports and studies. Need to find this information, perhaps it will lead me down the path of Gunslinger.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
