<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="st_stuff">
		<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Oblivion Lost Remake</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_producer">
		<text>Project author</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_hi_flyer">
		<text>hi_flyer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_project_lead">
		<text>The development of version 3.0 involved:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_designer">
		<text>hi_flyer - main developer: SDK, script, story implementation, game design, scripts, engine, shaders, dialogs, lighting, location compilation, geometry edits, locations, configs, ui design and customization, sound, etc.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_lead_programmers">
		<text>Cartoteka - addition of design documents, additional lit. content, models. 
Domestos - textures, voiceover.
Vinc - new models, website, media support.
ypaL62 - animations and models.
proger_Dencheek - engine, scripts. 
Vector - level12 modeling and design, r1 capsule model.
CuJIbBEP - corrections of vegetation models, geometry corrections. 
Vladislav Messer - new models and animations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_thanks">
		<text>Thanks to: Vx_SK98, Kirill Bespamyatnov, saas, Zone Chronicles Portal, 1RIDDICK11, DemonShrams, Shoker, Nikita Lebedin, Maxim Sukhodolov, DoubleT, Andrey Zotov, VEX, onetwo, Vladislav Suldin, RSFSR
Andrey Makarov, Stanislav Cherskov, Rishad Allaberdiev, Gallard Records, RuWar, Kyanan Veliyev, Ilya Gorz, Pavel Fazluktinov, 2clip, lvg_brest, Ray Twitty (aka Shadows), nummer, dsh, charsi, Sergey Krasheninnikov,
macron, Xray Oxygen team, OGSR engine team, Red_Virus, Modera, RuWar. And also to everyone who expected and believed in the project.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_thanks_sp">
		<text>Special thanks to: Hypothermist, CapitN_KANG, Luis, ANDrevenge, STALKER - SHOC, Juan Pablo, Alexander Shkaredny, Kotyachiy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_storyfake">
		<text>All events presented in the mod are fictional, all coincidences are coincidental. The mod is a free interpretation of not released project - S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Oblivion Lost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_vk">
		<text>Official VK project group - vk.com/olr_mod</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_thanksg">
		<text>Thanks for playing!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
